Marton family collection of United States and international performance programs M1801
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Marton family collection of United States and international performance programs
circa 1950-2015
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
M1801
7.71 Linear Feet (12 manuscript boxes, 1 half box, 1 flat box)
Scope and Contents
Box 1: Canada; New England; New York -- Box 2: California: mainly Los Angeles; some San Francisco -- Box 3: Chicago and other Midwest (Iowa, Illinois, Minnesota, Missouri) -- Box 4: Japan, 1975, programs, articles by Patricia Marton on Japanese and European theater and film, clippings on Japanese theater and other arts -- Boxes 5-7: London -- Box 8: London, Norway and Sweden, 1990's -- Box 9: New York -- Box 10: Film, productions with participation by Patricia Marton, The Puppet Theater of Japan by A.C. Scott, The Magic World of Hand Puppets by Marion Fischer, The Puppetry Journal, 1961, 1973, 1974 -- Box 11 [oversize materials]: Cannes Film Festival program, 1968; Chicago, Phil Silvers in Top Banana, circa 1950-1959; Japan, notes and photographs from Akira Wakabayashi Bunraku production, 1975; London, ballet, opera, and theater programs; Central School of Speech and Drama information packet, circa 1990-1999; Broadway production programs; New York, Broadway, ice skating, and Radio City programs, circa 1960-2000. Boxes 12-14: Programs, ephemera, photographs and clippings.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was a Gift of the Marton Family of Bloomington, Illinois to Stanford University, Special Collections in 2010.
Concert programs; Dance -- History; puppet theater -- History; Theater -- History; Theater programs
- Boston, Berkshires, Yale: Theater, dance, and symphony performances., circa 1980s-2000s (Box 1, Folders 1-3)
- California: LA and SF theater and dance programs., circa 1960s-2000s (Box 2)
- Canada: Theater and Toronto Festival of Storytelling, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 1, Folders 4-5)
- Chicago: Theater and dance, circa 1950s-2000s (Box 3, Folders 1-3, Box 11, Folder 2)
- Film: Catalogs and press packet from Sorrento, Cannes, Belgium, 1960s (Box 10, Folders 1-2, Box 11, Folder 1)
- Japan: Performance programs; writing and photographs on Japanese theater by Patricia Marton, 1975 (Box 11, Folders 3-4, Box 4)
- London: Theater; dance; music; opera, circa 1950s-2000s (Box 11, Folders 5-7, Box 8, Folders 1-4, Boxes 5-7, Folders 5-6)
- Midwest: Performance programs from IL; IA; MN; MO, circa 1950s-2000s (Box 3, Folders 4-7)
- New York: Theater; dance; music; opera; and ice skating, circa 1950s-2000s (Box 11, Folder 8, Box 1, Folders 6-7, Box 9)
- Norway & Sweden: Theater and dance, 1990s (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Productions with participation by Patricia Marton (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Puppetry: The Puppet Theatre of Japan, A.C. Scott; The Magic World of Hand Puppets, Marion Fischer; The Puppetry Journal, 1960s-1970s (Box 10, Folders 4-5)
- Theater programs: musicals, circa 1950-2015 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
- Theater playbills, circa 1953-1958 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Programs: dance, circa 1959-1991 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Programs: opera and symphony, circa 1952-2014 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Royal Parish Church of St. Martin-in-the-Fields: Vivien Leigh, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Radio City Music Hall, 1963, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Programs - Easter, in Swedish (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Performing Arts guides and season guides (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Wedding of Princess Margaret and Antony Armstrong-Jones souvenir programme, 1960-05-06 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Ticket stubs (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Ephemera relating to Patricia Marton's plays and performances, certificate from National Piano Playing Auditions; thank you card (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Ephemera relating to Patricia Marton's plays and performances, certificate from National Piano Playing Auditions; thank you card; Harmony HOuse and Museum of Repertoire Americana flyers (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Patricia Marton's writings about theater (Box 12, Folder 11)
- United States and London: souvenir programs of musicals, circa 1949-1963, many with autographs (Half-box 13, Folder 1-3)
- Ice capades programs (Half-box 13, Folder 4)
- Nidaros Cathedral Choir, 1994 - program (Half-box 13, Folder 4)
- Sheet music from musicals (Half-box 13, Folder 5)
- British Film Academy Awards 1966 - program (Half-box 13, Folder 6)
- Central School of Speech and Drama - promotional package (Half-box 13, Folder 7)
- Ten photographs of Japanese masks, many taken by Patricia Marton (Flat-box 14, Folder 1)
- Photographs including Tokyo Kid Brothers and a Japanese theater production (Flat-box 14, Folder 1)
- Newspaper articles including production of Showboat in Chicago in 1996 (Flat-box 14)